Herold J. Wiens Collection
Geography & Map Division Library of Congress
- Boundary Map of Chinese and Russian Border, Guangxu 16 (1890) by Hong Jun.:., 177; Format: Map; In Chinese.; Photocopy.
  Russia
- Lower Yangtze Valley-17th Century by Geography Department, Nanjing University.:., 178; Format: Map; In Chinese.; Photocopy-2 copies.
- China during Song Dynasty (960-1279):., 179; 1:3,000,000; Format: Map; In Chinese.; Inset maps of China and Formosa (Taiwan).
- Shanghai City Transportation Map by Shanghai Peoples Publishing House.:,., 180; Format: Map; In Chinese-Tourist Map.; Reprinted by Center for Chinese Research Materials, Washington, D.C.
- Nanking-Shanghai-Hangchow Area, 181; 1:400,000; Format: Map
- [Relief Maps of areas in Gansu, Shanxi, Shaaxi Provinces], 182; various; Format: Map; Thematic treatments including main river and tributaries showing soil composition, river bank slopes, river depths, erosion and other land characteristics; Sheets 1-4: Xifeng, Sheets 4-9: Wangjiagou River(Lishan county), Sheets 10-15:Xigou River(Sishan county),Sheets 16-23:Daohuanggou River(Hequ county), Sheets 24-28: Quingyugou River(Yulin county), Sheets 29-35:Shangjugou River(Jingbian county), Sheets
- Compensating Polar Planimeters with Tracer Point No. 62 0002 by Keuffel & Esser Co..:., 183; Format: Technical Drawing Instruments; Three parts, instruction book, and box.
- Stencil Kit, Leroy 3240 by Keuffel & Esser Co..:., 184; Format: Technical Drawing Instruments; Fifteen parts and box.
- Compass and Drawing Tools, No. 650 by Alteneder.:., 185; Format: Technical Drawing Instruments; Four parts and box.
- Anvil Railroad Pen, 5 1/4 in., No. 932 by Keuffel & Esser Co..:., 186; Format: Technical Drawing Instruments; One part and box.
- Four Dividers and Two Stencils by Keuffel & Esser Co. and Esco.:., 187; Format: Technical Drawing Instruments; Six parts.
- Precison Pantograph Small Type 500 by A. Ott.:., 188; Format: Technical Drawing Instruments; Ten parts ,instruction book, and box.
- Flexible Curve Rule, Transparent Edge, 12 in. No. N1924-12 by Keuffel & Esser Co..:., 189; Format: Technical Drawing Instruments; Two parts and box.
- Various subjects covering China by Harold Wiens and Students.:,., 190; Format: Textual Material; Subjects: Salt Industry in Ming China, The importance of Sui and T'ang Canal Systems, Liao Dynasty, Ming Dynasty, Chian Pre-History, Geography of the Shang, Ch'in, Chou, Sino -Japanese Relations, China Historical Generalizations, continued in Note 2; Post-Han and Five Dynasties, Sui & T'ang, Yung (Mongol), Sung N&S.
- Economic Geography of Southwest China, (Szechwan, Kweichow, Yunnan) Translated by JPRS by Edited by Sun Ching-chih, Compiled by Sun P'an-shou,Sun Ch'eng-lieh, Shen Wei-ch'eng, and Chang Pei.:., 191; 740 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Translation.; Loose pages in box.
- Agricultural Geography of Communist China by Liu Shi-chi.:,., 192; 29 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Translation.
- Peasant Families and Agrarian Community in the Process of Economic Development by Shigeru Ishikawa.:,., 193; 55 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Presented at the Conference May 23-29, 1973. in Bellagio, Italy.
- Structural and Technological Change in the Postwar U.S. Economy: An Input-Output Analysis by Dr. Roger H. Bezdek.:,., 194; 55 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Presented At the Annual Meeting of the AEA in Atlantic City, NJ.
- Scope for the Substitution of Labor and Equipment in Civil Construction-A Progress Report by World Bank, Prepared by: I.K. Sud, C.G. Harral, and B.P. Coukis.:,., 195; 28 Pages; Format: Textual Material
- Canton [Published by Kuang-chou Literary Press, Canton 1959, Translated by JPRS] by Communist China, Canton Branch of the Chinese People Association of Foreign Cultural Relations.:,., 196; 86 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Translation.
- Agricultural Geography of China by Chu Cho.:,., 197; 45 Pages; Format: Textual Material
- Statistical Analysis of Price System in Mainland China by Toshiyuki Mizoguchi.:., 198; 11 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Reprint Series No. 14.; Copier pages.
- China's Agricultural Improvement Program by Raymond T. Moyer.:,., 199; Pages 130-142; Format: Textual Material; Loose pages.
- The Government and Economy of Manchuria by Chao Kuo-chun.:,., 200; Pages 169-184; Format: Textual Material
- Economic Contrasts: China, India, and Japan by Hugh T. Patrick and Peter Schran.:,., 201; Pages 168-184; Format: Textual Material; Reprint from Journal of International Affairs, Vol .17, No. 2, 1963.
- Foreign and Domestic Debt in Communist China by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 202; 11 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Prepared by George N. Ecklund.
- Average Annual Money Earnings of Workers and Staff in Communist China 1949-60 by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 203; 11 Pages; Format: Textual Material
- Taxation in Communist China 1950-59 by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 204; 117 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Prepared by George N. Ecklund.
- The Short-Lived Liberal Phase in Economic Thinking in Communist China by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 205; 22 Pages; Format: Textual Material; CIA/RR 63-14.
- The Program for Water Conservancy in Communist China 1949-61 by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 206; 49 Pages; Format: Textual Material; CIA/RR 63-13.
- Research Aid. Methods of Constructing Economic Indexes from Incomplete Data by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 207; 22 Pages; Format: Textual Material; (ER) 74-64.
- Research Aid. People's Republic of China: Foreign Trade in Machinery and Equiptment Since 1952 by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 208; 34 Pages; Format: Textual Material; (ER) 75-60.
- Research Aid. Production of Machinery and Equiptment in the Peoples Republic of China by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 209; 31 Pages; Format: Textual Material; (ER) 75-63.
- Research Aid. People's Republic of China: Chemical Fertilizer Supplies, 1949-74 by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 210; 20 Pages; Format: Textual Material; A (ER) 75-70.
- Research Aid. Value Added by Work Brigades in Railroad and Highway Construction in China,1952-57 by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 211; 11 Pages; Format: Textual Material; 76-10150.
- Research Aid. China's Minerals and Metals Position in the World Market by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 212; 21 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 76-10150.
- Research Aid. People's Republic of China: Estimated Yuan Value of Foreign Trade In Machinery and Equiptment 1951-73 by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 213; 20 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 76-10250.
- Communist Aid to Less Developed Countries by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 214; 33 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 76-10372U.
- Research Aid. China: The Coal Industry by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 215; 23 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 76-10691.
- The International Energy Situation: Outlook to 1985 by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 216; 18 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 77-10240 U.
  World
- Prospects for Soviet Oil Production by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 217; 11 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 77-10270.; Map. Major Soviet Petroleum Deposits, Pipelines, Refineries.
- Research Aid. Handbook of Economic Statistics 1977 by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 218; 165 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 77-10537.
- China: A Preliminary Reconcilication of Official and CIA National Product Data by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 219; 9 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER M 79-10690.
- China: International Trade, 1976-77. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 220; 18 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 77-10674.
- Influence of Agrotechnology And Geoclimate on Grain Yield Potential in the USSR. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 221; 10 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 78-10058.
- China: In Pursuit of Economic Modernization. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 222; 17 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 89-10680.
- China: International Trade 1977-78. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 223; 23 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 78-10721.
- China: Economic Indicators. A Reference Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 224; 50 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 78-10750.; Map. Peoples Republic of China. Petroleum Industry.
- China: Agriculture in 1978. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 225; 15 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 79-10206.
- China; The Steel Industry In the 1970's and 1980's. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 226; 12 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 79-10245.
- China: International Trade Quarterly Review Third Quarter, 1979. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 227; 9 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER CIT 80-002.
- Electric Power for China's Modernization: The Hydroelectic Option. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 228; 25 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 80-10089U.; Map. China: Hydroelectic Power Plants.
- China: International Trade Quarterly Review Second Quarter, 1979. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 229; 30 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER CIT 80-001.
- China: International Trade Quarterly Review Fourth Quarter, 1979. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 230; 32 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER CIT 80-003.
- China: The Continuing Search for a Modernization Strategy. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 231; 21 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER 80-10248.
- China: International Trade Fourth Quarter, 1980. A Research Paper by National Foreign Assissment Center.:,., 232; 30 Pages; Format: Textual Material; ER CIT 81-003.
- Agriculture Situation. Review of 1978 and Outlook for 1979. People's Republic of China by United States.Department of Agriculture.:,., 233; 38 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Supplement 6 to WAS 18.; Editor CharlesY. Liu with various contributors.
- Agriculture Situation. Review of 1977 and Outlook for 1978. People's Republic of China by United States.Department of Agriculture.:,., 234; 36 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Supplement 6 to WAS 15.; Editor CharlesY. Liu with various contributors.
- Agriculture Situation. Review of 1974 and Outlook for 1975. People's Republic of China by United States.Department of Agriculture.:,., 235; 30 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Foreign Agricultural Economic Report No. 111.; Editor CharlesY. Liu with various contributors.
- River and Coastal Junks in China's Commerce by Herold J. Wiens.,., 236; Pages 248-264; Format: Textual Material; Reprint.
- China's Economy and Foreign Trade, 1978-79 by United States. Department of Agriculture.:,., 237; 27 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Written by Nai-Ruenn Chen.
- The Chinese Economy and Foreign Trade Perspective-1976 by United States Department of Commerce.:,., 238; 57 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Prepared under Supervision of William C. Clarke.
- Seven Articles on Land Reform.[Asia] by Asian Studies Center. Michigan State University.:,., 239; 80 Pages; Format: Textual Material; William D. Ross, Director, Asian Studies Center.
- The Rise of the Modern Chinese Business Class by Marion J. Levy, Jr. and Shih Kuo-Heng.:,., 240; 64 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Essays by Marion J. Levy, Jr. and Shih Kuo-Heng.
- The Rise of the New People's Democratic Economy 1927-1937 by Institue of Advance Projects.:,., 241; 76 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Lectures by Chung-kuo,Hupei University, China.; Translated by William W.L. Wan.
- Growth of the Construction Industry in Communist China by Kang Chao.:., 242; 17 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Extract from The China Quarterly, Ilford House, London England. Apr.-June, 1965. Pages 125-142.
- The Budgetary System of the People's Republic of China: A Preliminary Survey by Ching-Wen Kwang.:,., 243; 33 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Reprint from Public Finance, Universitad des Saarlandes, Saabrucken 15, Germand Vol.XV111, No.3-4 1963. Pages 253-286
- The Terms of Sino-Soviet Trade by Feng-Hwa Mah.:., 244; 17 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Reprint from The China Quarterly, The Eastern Press, Ltd. London, England. Jan.-March, 1964. Pages 174-191.
- A Study of the Rouble-Yuan Exchange Rate by Kang Chao and Feng-Hwa Mah.:., 245; 12 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Reprint from The China Quarterly, The Eastern Press, Ltd. London, England. Jan.-March, 1964. Pages 192-204.
- A Note on the Choice of Technology in China by Shigeru Ishikawa.,., 246; Pages 161-186; Format: Textual Material; Reprint from Frank Case & Co. Ltd., London, England.
- The Manchurian Iron and Steel Industry and its Resource Base by Allan Rodgers.,., 247; Pages 41-54; Format: Textual Material; Reprint.
- Birth Control in China by Michael Freeberne.,., 248; Pages 5-16; Format: Textual Material; Reprint.
- Elements of Instability in the Current Japanese Land Tenure System by John D. Eyre.,., 249; Pages 193-202; Format: Textual Material; Reprint.
- The Changing Role of the Former Japanese Landlord by John D. Eyre.,., 250; Pages 36-46; Format: Textual Material; Reprint.
- China's National Railways by H. J. von Lochow.:,., 251; 162 Pages; Format: Textual Material; LOC call number HE3285.L6.
- Cornell Workshop on Agricultural and Rural Development in the Republic of China by The Center for the Analysis of World Food Issues.:,., 252; 58 Pages; Format: Textual Material
- The size, composition, and growth of the population of mainland China by John S. Aird.:,., 253; 100 Pages; Format: Textual Material; LOC call number HB3637.A55 1973.
- Anshan Steel Factory in Communist China by Cheng, Chu-yuan.:,., 254; 88 Pages; Format: Textual Material; LOC call number HD9526.C64 A53.
- Economic Planning in Communist China by Hsia, Ronald.:,., 255; 71 Pages; Format: Textual Material; LOC call number HC427.H68.
- China: Area, Administration and National Building by Whitney, Joseph B.R..:,., 256; 198 Pages; Format: Textual Material; LOC call number DS706.5.W48.
- Cities of Mainland China: 1953 and 1958 by Ullman, Morris Benjamin.:,., 257; 46 Pages; Format: Textual Material; LOC call number HC331.U52 no.59.
- Communist China Map Folio by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 258; 40 Pages; various; Conic Egual Area; Format: Atlas
- Communist China Administrative Atlas by Central Intelligence Agency.:,., 259; 34 Pages; various; Format: Atlas
- Economic atlas of Szechuan--Shuo ming. Ssu-ch'uan ching chi ti t'u chi. by Pei-ch'ei, Chung-kuo ti li yen chiu so, Min-kuo 35.., 260; Format: Atlas; LOC call number G2308.S9 C56 1946. Copy 1
- Temperature and River Basins in China, 261; 12 Charts; Format: Chart
- East Asia by Goode Base Map Series.:,., 262; 1 map; Conic Projection; Format: Map; Henry M. Leppard, Editor
- [Circular Bar Graphs for Cities in China showing Months, Days and unknown markings], 263; 28 charts; Format: Chart; Temperature[?], Rainfall[?].
  Aisa
- The Geography of Kapingamarangi Atoll in the Eastern Carolines by Herold J. Wiens.:,., 264; 99 Pages; Format: Textual Material; Scientific Investigations in Micronesia.; Pacific Science Board and the National Research Council.